《星际迷航10：复仇女神》
参议员们 为了帝国 想想这些机遇吧
Senators, consider the opportunities for the Empire.
最终 各星球的的命运将靠罗穆卢斯和瑞摩斯联合起来
At last, the destinies of the planets Romulus and Remus will be united.
瑞摩斯的辛藏将给我们
Shinzon of Remus is offering us a chance
一个使我们比以前更加强大的机会
to make ourselves stronger than ever before.
拒绝将是愚蠢的
It would be madness to reject it.
我恳求你们不要让偏见和政治
I beg you not to let prejudice or politics
影响了这次联盟
interfere with this alliance.
和我们一起加入辛藏的的部队
By joining Shinzon's forces with ours,
就算联邦也无力阻碍我们...
not even the Federation will be able to stand in our way...
够了!
That's enough!
决议已经做出
The decision has been made.
军队是不会听从罗穆卢斯的政策行事的
The military does not dictate policy on Romulus.
参议院已经考虑了辛藏的提议并否决了它
The Senate has considered Shinzon's proposal and rejected it.
他和他的跟随者们将会遭到所有经过深思熟虑的力量的反对
He and his followers will be met with all deliberate force
让他们回到他们黑石老家
and sent back to that black rock they came from.
- 我讲清楚了吗? - 是的 先生
- Do I make myself clear? - Yes, sir.
如果不介意 执政官
If you will excuse me, Praetor.
我和索里大使有约
I have an appointment with the Tholian ambassador.
当然
Of course.
参议员们 还有谁要发言吗?
Senators, are there any others who wish to speak?
那么我建议对关于和瑟勒斯二世开放贸易谈判的提议进行投票表决
Then I call for a vote on the motion to open trade negotiations with Celes II.
你们都知道 瑞曼的矿藏到现在已经
As you know, the Reman mines
数月没有供应他们的配额了
have not been filling their quotas for months now.
我希望你们牢牢记住贸易委员会的裁决
I hope that you will all bear in mind the trade committee's findings.
就象我们不想要...
As much as we don't want...
谁去叫下保卫?
Would someone alert security?
把特洛瑞参议员叫回来
Bring back Senator Tal Aura.
职责
Duty.
一艘星际飞船船长的生活充满了神圣的职责
A starship captain's life is filled with solemn duty.
我曾指挥船员们战斗
I have commanded men in battle.
我曾和死敌们进行和平条约的谈判
I have negotiated peace treaties between implacable enemies.
我曾代表联邦
I have represented the Federation
和27种外星物种进行首次接触
in first contact with 27 alien species.
但是以前的这一切都不能我和今天神圣的职责相比...
But none of this compares with my solemn duty today...
做一名伴郎
as best man.
现在 我知道在这样的场合下
Now, I know on an occasion such as this,
我本该亲切
it is expected that I be gracious
而由衷的祝福这对天作之合
and fulsome in my praise on the wonders of this blessed union.
但是你们俩是否考虑过你们给我了什么呢?
But have the two of you considered what you are doing to me?
当然 你们是快乐的 但是我呢?
Of course you're happy, but what about my needs?
这简直就是一个该死的不便之处
This is all a damned inconvenience.
我的意思是 当你们快乐的在泰坦号上定居的时候
While you're happily settling in on the Titan,
而我正在训练我新的大副 你们都认识他
I will be training my new First Officer. You all know him.
他是专横而严格的人 从不也绝不会让我
He's a tyrannical martinet who will never
从不也绝不会让我放弃任务
ever allow me to go on away missions.
那是规章 先生 星际舰队法规第四章第十二款...
That is the regulation, sir. Starfleet Code, Section 12, Paragraph...
- 数据先生? - 长官?
- Mr.Data. - Sir?
- 闭嘴 - 是的 长官
- Shut up. - Yes, sir.
这15年我一直想说那个
Fifteen years I've been waiting to say that.
不 认真的
No, seriously.
维尔 蒂安娜 要重新考虑还来得及
Will, Deanna, there's still time to reconsider.
要吗?
Yes?
- 不要 - 不要
- No. - No.
不要? 哦 非常好 那么
No? Oh, very well, then.
维尔·瑞克 你作为我的得力助手已经15年了
Will Riker, you have been my trusted right arm for 15 years.
你保证我的航线正确而平稳
You have kept my course true and steady.
蒂安娜·婥维 你是我的向导和良知
Deanna Troi, you've been my guide and my conscience.
你帮助我认识到我自己优点
You've helped me recognize the better parts of myself.
你们是我的家人
You are my family.
以船上的惯例
And in best maritime tradition,
我希望你们俩美好的开始
I wish you both clear horizons.
我的好朋友 去获取幸福吧!
My good friends, make it so.
为新娘和新郎干杯!
The bride and groom.
- 为新娘和新郎干杯 - 为新娘和新郎干杯
- To the bride and groom. 　- To the bride and groom.
你曾想过再婚吗?
You ever think about getting married again?
没有 23是我的界线
No. Twenty-three was my limit.
沃夫?
Worf?
- 你还好吗? - 若米兰酒应该被禁售
- Are you all right? - Romulan ale should be illegal.
是的
It is.
- 那是个愉快的干杯 - 那是发自内心的
- That was a lovely toast. - It was from the heart.
你不用担心
And you needn't worry.
我会给你新的顾问详细地介绍她需要知道的一切
I'm going to brief your new counselor on everything she needs to know.
哦 就象你一样 你已经太了解我了
Oh, like hell you are. You already know too much about me.
但是我认为在贝塔斯特的庆典期间我不会再做演讲了
I take it that there will be no speeches during the ceremony on Betazed?
是的 不演讲 也不用穿好衣服了
No. No speeches and no clothes.
女士们 先生们 以及受邀请的三性物种...
Ladies and gentlemen and invited transgendered species,
我在学习地球人和贝塔左德结婚习俗期间
in my study of Terran and Betazoid conjugal rites
我发现向快乐的新婚夫妇送礼物是一个传统
I've discovered it is traditional to present the happy couple with a gift.
考虑到瑞克指挥官对古典音乐的偏爱
Given Commander Riker's affection for archaic musical forms,
我选了下面这首歌作为我给他们的礼物
I have elected to present the following as my gift
为他们的结合表示祝贺
in honor of their conjugation.
结合!
Conjugation!
∮ 从来没见过太阳照耀出如此光亮 ∮
∮ Never saw the sun shining so bright ∮
∮ 从来没见过事情发展如此顺利 ∮
∮ Never saw things going so right ∮
∮ 注意到日子匆匆忙忙 ∮
∮ Noticing the days hurrying by ∮
∮ 当你沉入爱河中 呀 他们是怎样飞上 ∮
∮ When you're in love, my how they fly ∮
∮ 噢 蓝色的天空对着我笑 ∮
∮ Blue skies Smiling at me ∮
欧文·柏林...
Irving Berlin.
∮ 我能看见的只有蓝色的天空 ∮
∮ Nothing but blue skies Do I see ∮
这是传统 沃夫
It's tradition, Worf.
你 以及其他人 应该懂得那些
You, of all people, should appreciate that.
我不会这样做的!
I will not do it.
不做什么 沃夫先生?
Won't do what, Mr.Worf?
船长 我认为对于一个星际战舰的船员来说
Captain, I do not think it is appropriate
赤裸出现是不恰当的
for a Starfleet officer to appear naked.
哦 行了
Oh, come now.
像你这样一位高大 帅气 魁梧的家伙? 你还害怕什么呢?
A big, handsome, strapping fellow like you? What can you be afraid of?
船长 我从科洛仁系
Captain, I'm picking up an unusual electromagnetic signature
获得一个罕见的电磁信号
from the Kolarin system.
- 什么类型的信号? - 正电子
- What sort of signature? - Positronic.
它非常微弱
It's very faint.
但是我已经把它从科洛仁系的第三行星里隔离出来了
But I've isolated it to the third planet in the Kolarin system.
- 我们对它有什么了解? - 未知
- What do we know about it? - Uncharted.
我们得靠的更近一下以获得更详细的扫描
We'll have to get closer for a more detailed scan.
你有什么意见?
Theories?
对于只有像我这样的机器人
Since positronic signatures have only been known to emanate
才会发出正电子信息来看
from androids such as myself,
合理的推测就是在科洛仁三号上有一个机器人
it is logical to theorize there is an android on Kolarus III.
正如我担心的 船长
Just what I was afraid of. Captain,
向科洛仁系的转移
diverting to the Kolarin system
使我们离若米兰中心区非常的近
takes us awfully close to the Romulan Neutral Zone.
在我们这面依然是好的 我认为 呃...
It's still well on our side. I think...
我认为很值得去看看 不要担心 大副
I think it's worth taking a look. Don't worry, Number One.
我们依然需要你到贝塔斯德去
We'll still have you to Betazed with plenty of time to spare.
谢谢 长官
Thank you, sir.
那儿我们将的尊重贝塔斯德的传统
Where we will all honor the Betazoid tradition.
现在 如果你不介意 我要去健身了
Now, if you'll excuse me, I'll be in the gym.
布朗森先生 确定一条到科洛仁系的路线 5号航线
Mr.Branson, lay in a course for the Kolarin system, warp 5.
你有什么看法吗 数据? 一位失踪多年的亲戚?
What do you think, Data? A long-lost relative?
我在这个行星的表面超过好几公里的范围处
I'm reading six distinct positronic signatures
发现了六个不同地方发出正电子信号
spread out over a few kilometers on the planet's surface.
我们知道多少关于科洛仁三号行星人口的消息?
What do we know about the population of Kolarus III?
有小群的孤立的星球人
Isolated pockets of humanoids.
看上去是一种
It appears to be a pre-warp civilization
在工业发展早期被歪曲了的文明
at an early stage of industrial development.
船长 我建议不要使用传输机
Captain, I wouldn't recommend using the transporter.
那些离子风暴看起来不怎么友好
That ion storm doesn't look very neighborly.
它可能没有太多警告的情况下 出现在我们面前
It could head in our direction without much warning.
知道了
Understood.
- 数据 沃夫先生 你们和我一起 - 船长 我不得不提醒你...
- Data, Mr.Worf, you're with me. - Captain, I don't have to remind you...
我很感激你的关心 大副
I appreciate your concern, Number One.
- 但是 呃 我已经渴望试试坐一下这个亚尔古舟了 - 我打赌
- But I've been itching to try the Argo. - I'll bet.
船长的特权 那有不可预知的危险
Captain's prerogative. There's no foreseeable danger.
如果你发生了什么不测 你的妻子可决不会原谅我
And your wife would never forgive me if anything were to happen to you.
你来控制飞船... 婥维先生
You have the Bridge, Mr.Troi.
我总是对人类以不安全的速度
I will always be puzzled by the human predilection
来驾驶交通工具感到迷惑不解
for piloting vehicles at unsafe velocities.
那高出的地方 长官 半公里
Over that rise, sir. Half a kilometer.
电磁射线范围在我的 三角自动记录器上乱动
The radiant electromagnetic field is interfering with my tricorder.
但我们离信号只有几米的距离
We are within a few meters of the signal.
把它找出来 让我们仔细找找
Fan out. Let's search around.
- 这好像是个机械手 - 非常正确
- It appears to be a robotic arm. - Very astute.
沃夫先生 把它带到车上
Mr.Worf, bring it to the vehicle.
这好像有点不对劲
This doesn't feel right.
最后一个信号大约在北方100米处 长官
The final signature is approximately 100 meters to the north, sir.
是你
It's you.
惊人的相似
The resemblance is striking.
- 太神奇了 - 太神奇了
- Fascinating. - Fascinating.
上车
To the vehicle.
我想是试试危险速度的时候了
I think it's time to try some unsafe velocities.
为什么你有一个发亮的头?
Why do you have a shiny head?
现在不是交谈的时候
This is not the appropriate time for a conversation.
为什么?
Why?
因为船长必须集中精力驾驶这辆车
Because the Captain has to concentrate on piloting the vehicle.
- 为什么? - 因为...
- Why? - Cause...
数据!
Data!
对不起 长官
Sorry, sir.
我说错什么了吗?
Have I said something wrong?
数据
Data.
你知道 全面考虑来看 数据 我认为你的那双眼睛更漂亮
You know, all things considered, Data, I think you have nicer eyes.
我们的眼睛是一样的 博士
Our eyes are identical, Doctor.
我们获得些什么信息 郭蒂?
So what have we got, Geordi?
呃 我得说他有和数据一样的内部机械结构
I'd say he has the same internal mechanics as Data
但是正电子的设计水平不如数据
but not as much positronic development.
神经系统线路不是很复杂
The neural pathways aren't nearly as sophisticated.
我是说他是一个原型
I'd say he's a prototype.
可能宋博士在制造数据之前创造的东西
Something Dr. Soong created prior to Data.
你有名字吗 先生?
Do you have a name, sir?
我叫B-4
I am B-4.
B-四?
B-4?
宋博士老是取一些古怪的名字 好像没有终结似的
Dr. Soong's penchant for whimsical names seems to have no end.
你能告诉我们你怎么到我们发现你的那颗行星上的吗?
Can you tell us how you came to be on the planet where we found you?
我不知道
I do not know.
你还记得一些在你到那颗星球上前你是怎么样的吗?
Do you remember anything of your life before you were on the planet?
- 不记得了 - 为什么那个高个有一脸的络腮胡子?
- No. - Why does the tall man have a furry face?
大副 随时向我报告 呃 郭蒂 重新把他组装起来
Number One, keep me informed. And, Geordi, reassemble him.
是 长官
Aye, sir.
B-4 你知道我是谁吗?
B-4, do you know who I am?
你是我
You are me.
不
No.
我叫数据
My name is Data.
我是你的兄弟
I am your brother.
伯爵灰茶 热的
Tea, Earl Grey, hot.
船长 你有一个来自星际舰队指挥部来的最高级通信
Captain, you have an Alpha Priority communication from Starfleet Command
接通
Acknowledged.
简维舰队司令 很高兴再次见到你
Admiral Janeway, how good to see you again.
吉恩·卢克 你在罗穆卢斯旅行怎么样了?
Jean-Luc. How would you like a trip to Romulus?
- 包不包括剩下的舰队? - 一次外交任务
- With or without the rest of the fleet? - A diplomatic mission.
我们已经受到邀请了 信不信由你
We've been invited, believe it or not.
好像出现了一些内部政治动荡
Seems there's been some kind of internal political shake-up.
新的执政官 一些人叫他辛藏
The new Praetor, someone called Shinzon,
已经邀请一位联邦使节
has requested a Federation envoy.
- 新的执政官? - 这还有更多消息 他是瑞曼人
- New Praetor? - Here's more. He's Reman.
相信我 我们对此也不了解
Believe me, we don't understand it, either.
你是离他最近的飞船
You're the closest ship.
因此我想你去听听他要说些什么
So I want you to go and hear what he has to say.
考察一下他是否真的有诚意
Get the lay of the land.
如果帝国变得不稳定的话 会对整个宇宙造成麻烦的
If the Empire becomes unstable, it could mean trouble for the entire quadrant.
明白
Understood.
我们正在向你发出我们所有的情报
We're sending you all the intelligence we have.
但是依然不够
But it's not much.
不用我告诉你要注意背后的情况了吧 吉恩·卢克
I don't need to tell you to watch your back, Jean-Luc.
不用了
Hardly.
索纳人 伯济人 若米兰人...
The Son'a, the Borg, the Romulans.
你好像总是得到所有这些容易的任务
You seem to get all the easy assignments.
只是运气 舰队司令
Just lucky, Admiral.
希望运气常在 简维中断通讯
Let's hope that luck holds. Janeway out.
舵手 绘出新的路线 我们去罗穆卢斯 8号航线
Helmsman, lay in a new course. Take us to Romulus. Warp 8.
- 是 长官 路线绘制并载入 - 罗穆卢斯?
- Aye-aye, sir. Course plotted and laid in. - Romulus?
恐怕奥珀尔海的事必须等等了 大副
I'm afraid The Opal Sea will have to wait, Number One.
前进
Engage.
你可以看出 瑞摩斯星的一面总是面对太阳
As you can see, one side of Remus always faces the sun.
由于他们的世界一半处在极高的温度下
Due to the extreme temperatures on that half of their world,
所以瑞曼人总是生活在这行星黑暗面
the Remans live on the dark side of the planet.
虽然通过智能扫描证明这颗星球的
Almost nothing is known of the Reman homeworld,
蒂里塞矿藏和重型武器制造方面很发达
although intelligence scans have proven
但我们对瑞曼人家园几乎还是一无所知
the existence of dilithium mining and heavy weapons construction.
瑞曼人他们自己也认为他们帝国的等级制度
The Remans themselves are considered
非常不受欢迎
an undesirable caste in the hierarchy of the Empire.
但是他们也因在主权战争中强大的战士而名声大噪
But they also have a reputation for being formidable warriors.
瑞曼人的部队在过去大多数激烈的战争中
In the Dominion War, Reman troops were used as assault forces
通常扮演着进攻的力量
in the most violent encounters.
炮灰而已
Cannon fodder.
是的 但一个瑞曼人怎么成为执政官的呢? 我搞不明白
Yeah, but how did a Reman get to be Praetor? I don't get it.
我们不得不假设他有若米兰人的合作者
We have to assume he had Romulan collaborators.
为什么?
Coup d'état?
执政官的力量总是是若米兰人的舰队
The Praetor's power has always been the Romulan fleet.
他们一定是在辛藏的幕后并帮他推翻了参议院
They must have been behind Shinzon for him to have overthrown the Senate.
我们对辛藏了解多少?
What have we learned about Shinzon?
星际舰队情报部只能
Starfleet intelligence was only able to provide
提供他的部分军事记录报告
a partial account of his military record.
我们可以推断他是一位比较年轻而能干的指挥官
We can infer he is relatively young and a capable commander.
在战争中他打了12场主要的战役 全都获胜
He fought 12 major engagements in the war. All successful.
除此之外 我们一无所知
Beyond that, we know nothing.
喔 看起来好像我们真的是在向未知的地区航行
Well, it seems as though we're truly sailing into the unknown.
加油干 我会很感激你们所能提供的一切 散会
Keep at it. Anything you can give me will be appreciated. Dismissed.
我依然不敢相信船长会同意下载记忆
I still can't believe the Captain went along with a memory download.
皮卡特船长同意是因为 B-4很可能是
Captain Picard agrees that the B-4 was probably designed
和我一样都是自我改进型
with the same self-actualization parameters as myself.
如果我的记忆痕迹能成功的整合到他的正电子矩阵中去 他应该能获得我所有的能力
If my memory engrams are successfully integrated into his positronic matrix,
他应该能获得我所有的能力
he should have all my abilities.
是的 但是他也会同样拥有你所有的记忆
Yeah. But he would also have all of your memories as well.
- 你对那个感觉舒服吗? - 我什么也感觉不到 郭蒂
- You feel comfortable with that? - I feel nothing, Geordi.
我相信只要他拥有了我的记忆痕迹
It is my belief that with my memory engrams
他将能成为更加完全的个体
he'll be able to function as a more complete individual.
- 你是说 一个和你差不多的个体 - 是的
- An individual more like you, you mean? - Yes.
可能他不会像你 数据
Maybe he's not supposed to be like you, Data.
可能他有他自己的行为方式
Maybe he's supposed to be exactly the way he is.
也有可能
That might be so.
但是我认为他应该有开发他潜能的机会
But I believe he should have the opportunity to explore his potential.
好了 我们完成了
Okay. We're done.
B-4 你知道你在哪里吗?
B-4, do you know where you are?
我在一间充满灯光的房间里
I am in a room with lights.
你记得我们的父亲吗?
Can you remember our father?
- 我们的父亲? - 是的 宋博士
- Our father? - Yes. Dr. Soong.
不知道
No.
你知道这艘飞船的船长的名字吗?
Do you know the name of the Captain of this vessel?
船长... 不知道
Captain... No.
数据 他刚刚载入了许多程序
Data, he's assimilating a lot of programming.
记住 他是个原型 远不及你复杂
Remember, he's a prototype, a lot less sophisticated than you are.
我们只是不知道是否他的矩阵能否适应
We just don't know if his matrix will be able to adapt.
我真的需要给他一些时间
We really need to give him some time.
郭蒂 这个是干什么用的?
Geordi, what purpose does this serve?
- 什么? - 这个
- What? - This.
那是一个多余的记忆接口
That's a redundant memory port.
可能是临时的记忆存储器以防他的神经线路过载
Maybe the provisional memory storage is in case his neural pathways overload.
你不介意我把他留在这里一会儿吧
Do you mind if I keep him here for a while?
进行一些诊断?
Run a few diagnostics?
不 我不介意
No, I do not mind.
数据
Data.
不 你必须留下来和拉佛吉指挥官待在一起
No. You must remain with Commander La Forge.
他会帮助你的
He is going to try to help you.
船长日志 星际日期 56844.9
Captain's Log. Stardate 56844.9.
企业号已经达到罗穆卢斯星
The Enterprise has arrived at Romulus
正在等待指派坐标
and is waiting at the designated coordinates.
我们发出的所有友好信息都没有得到回应
All our hails have gone unanswered.
我们已经等了17小时了
We've been waiting for 17 hours.
- 顾问? - 他们在外面 长官
- Counselor? - They're out there, sir.
船长 我建议升起防护罩
Captain, I recommend we raise shields.
不急 沃夫先生
Not yet, Mr.Worf.
船长 虽然因该尊重外交协议
Captain, with all due respect to diplomatic protocol,
但联邦议会没有坐在这里 而我们在
the Federation Council isn't sitting out here, we are.
耐心 外交是一个需付出极大耐心职业
Patience. Diplomacy is a very exacting occupation.
- 我们得等待 - 船长
- We will wait. - Captain.
- 升起防护罩 - 不
- Raising shields. - No.
- 船长 - 战术分析 沃夫先生
- Captain. - Tactical analysis, Mr.Worf.
52个干扰箱 27个光子鱼雷炸弹舱
Fifty-two disruptor banks, 27 photon torpedo bays,
一级和二级防护罩
primary and secondary shields.
她是一个掠夺者
She's a predator.
我们收到通讯联络
We are being hailed.
接到屏幕上
On-screen.
企业号
Enterprise,
我们是瑞曼人的单刃刀号战舰
we are the Reman warbird, Scimitar.
- 执政官辛藏 我很高兴... - 我不是辛藏
- Praetor Shinzon, I'm pleased to... - I am not Shinzon.
我是他的副手
I am his viceroy.
我们会发出一个传送坐标
We are sending transport coordinates.
- 废话倒很少 - 谈判队到4号传送室
- Not very chatty. - Away team, Transporter Room 4.
我希望你能原谅这里的黑暗
I hope you'll forgive the darkness.
我们对光线感到不舒服
We are not comfortable in the light.
- 执政官辛藏? - 船长皮卡特
- Praetor Shinzon? - Captain Picard.
吉恩·卢克·皮卡特
Jean-Luc Picard.
我一直以为你应该更高些 是不是很奇怪?
I'd always imagined you a little taller. Isn't that odd?
你不用偷偷摸摸的扫描我 数据指挥官
Now, you may scan me without subterfuge, Commander Data.
- 你和我想象中的不一样 - 不一样?
- You are not as we imagined you. - No?
你是人类
You are human.
你为什么叫我们到这里来?
Why have you asked us to come here?
执政官?
Praetor?
- 我从来没有见过人类女性 - 我只是半人类
- I've never met a human woman before. - I'm only half human.
来自贝塔斯德的蒂安娜·婥维
Deanna Troi of Betazed.
有移情和心灵感应能力 飞船的顾问
Empathic and telepathic abilities. Ship's counselor.
只是我知道的一切 但我从来没有想到你是如此漂亮
All this I knew. But I never knew you were so beautiful.
你好像对我们各个船员非常的熟悉
You seem quite familiar with our personnel.
哦 我是 瑞克指挥官
Oh, I am, Commander Riker.
我可以摸摸你的头发吗?
May I touch your hair?
我们到罗穆卢斯星是来解决有关重大问题的
We came to Romulus on a matter we were assured was of great importance.
如果你对作为联邦代表的我们有什么话要说的话
If you have anything to say to usas representatives of the Federation,
我建议你现在就说
I suggest you do it now.
是的 对不起 船长
Yes. I'm sorry, Captain.
我们要谈的太多了
There is so much we need to talk about.
我很想知道我们要谈些什么
I would be interested to know what we are talking about.
联合 船长
Unity, Captain.
推倒我们之间的隔阂之墙重新承认我们是一体的
Tearing down the walls between us to recognize that we are one.
我正说的是使我们变成一样的事情...
I'm talking of the thing that makes us the same.
和平 我们想要和平
Peace. We want peace.
现在 你肯定认为这一切听起来难以置信
Right now you're thinking this all sounds too good to be true,
但是你也在想
but you're also thinking
大有希望的和平机会是不能忽视的
that the chance for peace is too promising to ignore.
我说的对吗?
Am I right?
是的
Yes.
或许是我们该打个照面的时候了
Then, perhaps it's time to add some illumination to our discussion.
电脑 把照明提高到4级
Computer, raise the lighting four levels.
当我还很小的时候 我患一种奇怪的病
When I was very young, I was stricken with an odd disease.
我对声音极其敏感
I developed a hyper-sensitivity to sound.
使得最轻微的耳语也会对我造成的极大痛苦
Even the slightest whisper caused me agony.
没有人知道该怎么办
No one could do anything about it.
最后 我被带去看一个医生 他对地球人的疾病有一些经验
Finally, I was taken to a doctor who had some experience of Terran illnesses.
他诊断我得了夏拉夫特综合症
And he diagnosed me with Shalaft's Syndrome.
你知道那个吗 船长?
Do you know of it, Captain?
是的
Yes.
那么你知道那是一种非常罕见的综合症
Then you know it's a very rare syndrome.
遗传的
Genetic.
显而易见 家庭的所有男性成员都会得这种病
Apparently, all the male members of a family have it.
最终 我被治愈了 所以现在我能像你一样听了 船长
Eventually, I was treated and now I can hear as well as you can, Captain.
我能像你一样看了
I can see as well as you can.
我能感觉一切你所感觉的东西
I can feel everything you feel.
实际上
In fact,
实际上 我和你的感觉一模一样...
I feel exactly what you feel.
不是吗 吉恩·卢克?
Don't I, Jean-Luc?
明天来罗穆卢斯星上用餐吧 只有我们俩
Come to dinner tomorrow on Romulus. Just the two of us.
或者我应该说 只有我们一个人?
Or should I say, just the one of us?
我想你正想要这个
I think you'll be wanting this.
明天见 船长 我们有许多要讨论的
Until tomorrow then, Captain. We have much to discuss.
电脑 把照明恢复到初始水平
Computer, return lighting to previous level.
毫无疑问 船长
There's no doubt, Captain.
这正是你那夏拉夫特综合症所具有的好斗性情
Right down to your aggressive strain of Shalaft's Syndrome.
他是一个克隆人
He's a clone.
他们可能用了一根发囊或者一些皮肤细胞
They probably used a hair follicle or a skin cell.
- 为什么? - 我会找到答案的 大副
- Why? - I intend to find out, Number One.
向星际舰队通报这个情况
Inform Starfleet of the situation.
我要知道他到底是从哪里来的
I need to know where the hell he came from.
顾问
Counselor.
我们支持你 辛藏 当你暗杀参议员时
We supported you, Shinzon, when you assassinated the Senate.
你告诉我们是进攻联邦的最好时机了
You told us the timing was perfect for an attack on the Federation.
我不明白为什么现在你推迟了
I don't understand why now you delay.
你不必明白
You don't have to understand.
并且把企业号 带到了这里
And bringing the Enterprise here,
这样做的目的是什么?
what possible purpose could that serve?
- 我有一个打算 - 那或许你会开导一下我们
- I have a purpose. - Then, perhaps you'll enlighten us.
你给我安静点!
Silence, Romulan!
你真该学一下耐性了 指挥官
You really must learn patience, Commander.
过一下每天18小时在一位若米兰护卫鞭打下的生活
Spend 18 hours every day under the lash of a Romulan guard
或许你很快就会明白什么是耐性了
and you'll soon understand patience.
给我出去
Now go.
德纳储指挥官
Commander Donatra.
请留下
Please remain.
有个词我希望你考虑一下
There's a word I want you to consider.
忠诚 这是我对那些为我服务的人的要求
Allegiance. It's something I demand from those who serve me.
- 我为你服务吗? - 是的
- Do I serve you? - Yes.
并且我诚恳地认为
And, I think, faithfully.
瑟闰指挥官 从另一方面来说...
Commander Suran, on the other hand,
让我犹豫不定
gives me pause.
这有另外一个词 执政官
Here's another word, Praetor.
信任
Trust.
你信任我吗?
Do you trust me?
到底有多信任?
How far does that trust extend?
到底能多信任?
How deep does it go?
一位指挥官必须做些什么来证明她自己对你的忠诚呢?
What must a commander do to prove herself faithful to you?
一个女人又必须怎么证明呢?
What must a woman do?
你不是一个女人
You are not a woman.
你只是一个若米兰人
You are a Romulan.
忠诚的为我服务 你会得到奖赏的
Serve me faithfully and you will be rewarded.
那双可爱的眼睛好好看着瑟闰指挥官
Keep those lovely eyes on Commander Suran.
只要一发现他有背叛的迹象...
And at the first sign of treachery...
就干掉他
Dispose of him?
那你就能证明你自己了
Then you will have proven yourself.
出去吧
Now go.
还有 指挥官
And, Commander,
如果你再碰到我
if you ever touch me again,
我会杀了你的
I'll kill you.
不知若米兰人怎么得到你的DNA
The Romulans had somehow gained possession of your DNA
因此我就被创造了出来
and I had been created.
一旦我准备好了 他们就会用我来替代你
And when I was ready, they were going to replace you with me.
把一位若米兰的代表放在星际舰队的核心
Put a Romulan agent at the heart of Starfleet.
- 那是一个大胆的计划 - 然后发生了什么?
- It was a bold plan. - What happened?
就像在罗穆卢斯星这里经常发生一样...
As happens frequently on Romulus,
一个新的政府获得了权利 他们决定放弃这个计划
a new government came to power. They decided to abandon the plan.
他们害怕我可能被发现
They were afraid that I might be discovered
并将导致战争
and that it would lead to war.
和你记忆中那张脸不太一样吧
Not quite the face you remember.
不太一样
Not quite.
一生的暴虐造就了这一切
A lifetime of violence will do that.
他们打破了我的鼻子 我的下巴...
They broke my nose, my jaw.
但是还是有那么多一样的地方
But so much is the same.
眼睛..
The eyes.
- 你肯定认得这双眼睛 - 是的
- Surely you recognize the eyes? - Yes.
我们的眼睛反映了我们的一生 不是吗?
Our eyes reflect our lives, don't they?
你的眼睛是如此的自信
And yours are so confident.
因此我没有你期望的那么高
So, I'm not as tall as you expected?
呃 我总是希望我能达到2米
I had always hoped I might hit two meters.
也希望我那么高
As had I.
你是怎么到瑞摩斯星上的?
How did you end up on Remus?
他们把我送到那儿去等死
They sent me there to die.
区区一个人类怎么能在蒂里塞矿藏存活下去?
How could a mere human survive the dilithium mines?
那倒不是什么要紧的 但我却再不是
Not that it mattered
他们对抗联邦计划一部分
as I was no longer part of their plans against the Federation.
在那些只有该死的人生活的可怕的深度下
In those terrible depths lived only the damned.
和那些瑞曼奴隶一起 我被定了罪
Together with the Reman slaves,
在若米兰护卫的寸步不离的监视下
I was condemned to an existence of unceasing labor and starvation
进行持续劳动并且遭受饥饿的的折磨
under the brutal heel of the Romulan guards.
只有最最强壮的人才有生存的希望
Only the very strongest had any hope of survival.
当他们把我带到那儿时 我仅仅只是一个小孩
I was only a child when they took me.
从那时起我就近10年的时间再也没有见过太阳和星星了
Then I didn't see the sun or the stars again for nearly 10 years.
若米兰护卫唯一比讨厌瑞曼人更讨厌的人
The only thing the Romulan guards hated more than the Remans
就是我
was me.
但是有一个人可怜了我
But one man took pity on me.
这人以后成为了我的总督
The man that became my viceroy.
他从那些残酷的护卫下保护了我
He protected me from the cruelty of the guards
并教会我如何生存
and taught me how to survive.
在那黑暗的地方 我自己什么也不是
And in that dark place where there was nothing of myself,
我找到了我的瑞曼兄弟们
I found my Reman brothers.
他们给了我所知道的唯一真正的仁慈
They showed me the only true kindness I've ever known.
你这样做是为了解放瑞曼人?
You're doing this to liberate the Remans?
那是我所做的一切之后唯一的想法
That is the single thought behind everything I have done.
从在一个秘密基地建立单刃刀号 到组建我的军队
From building the Scimitarat a secret base to assembling my army.
最终武力占领罗穆卢斯星
Finally, coming to Romulus in force.
我知道他们决不会给我们自由 我必须争取它
I knew they would never give us our freedom. I would have to take it.
那么为了你的自由死了多少若米兰人呢?
How many Romulans died for your freedom?
太多了
Too many.
但是关键是 最终帝国逐渐认识到会有一个更好的办法
But the point is that finally the Empire is realizing that there is a better way.
那个办法就是和平
And that way is peace.
- 你不相信我 - 我没有理由相信
- You don't trust me. - I have no reason to.
你有充分的理由
You have every reason.
如果你经历了我的生活以及体验了我人民的痛苦
If you had lived my life and experienced the suffering of my people
你将会站到我这边的
you'd be standing where I am.
同样要是你经历了我的生活
And if you had lived my life
你也会明白我的对联邦的责任
you would understand my responsibility to the Federation.
我不能让我的个人感情 不恰当地影响了我决定
I cannot allow my personal feelings to unduly influence my decisions.
我所有的一切都是我的个人感情
All I have are my personal feelings.
我想要知道做为人类的意义是什么
I want to know what it means to be human.
瑞曼人给了我未来
The Remans have given me a future.
- 但是我能告诉你我的过去 - 我可以告诉你我的过去
- But you can tell me about my past. - I can tell you about my past.
- 我们皮卡特族人都是勇士吗? - 我想我自己是个探险家
- Were we Picards always warriors? - I think of myself as an explorer.
那么 我们一直是探险家了?
Were we always explorers?
我是第一个离开太阳系的皮卡特族人
I was the first Picard to leave our solar system.
在家族里还引起了不小的轰动
It caused quite a stir in the family.
但是我把我的青春花在了...
But I'd spent my youth...
仰望天上星星梦想有关上面的东西
Looking up at the stars, dreaming about what was up there, about...
梦想新世界
New worlds.
我努力相信你 辛藏
I'm trying to believe you, Shinzon.
联邦有个最美好的梦想
If there is one ideal that the Federation holds most dear,
让所有的人
it is that all men,
所有的种族都能联合起来
all races, can be united.
有什么比一位星际舰队船长站在
What better example?
若米兰参议院更好的例子了
A Starfleet captain standing in the Romulan Senate.
没有什么能让我感到比友好的握着你的手更自豪的事了
Nothing would make me more proud than to take your hand in friendship.
渐渐地
In time.
信任将积累
When that trust has been earned.
船长 在主电脑中我们遭到一个没有授权的侵入
Captain, we have had an unauthorized access into the main computer.
来源?
Source?
需要花些时间来确认 船长
It's gonna take some time to figure that out, Captain.
数据流是经过所有飞船的分站改道发送来的
The data stream was re-routed through sub-stations all over the ship.
- 用什么程序侵入的? - 那正是我不能确定的
- What programs were accessed? - That's what I can't figure out.
好像是基本的恒星绘图法
It's mostly just basic stellar cartography.
从殖民太空跟踪站通过星象图 通信协议
Star charts, communications protocols,
以及一些卫星上行链路发出的
some uplinks from colony tracking stations.
并不是禁用物质
It's not even restricted material.
不管怎么样 我们必须找到来源 及时向我报告
Nevertheless, we must learn the source. Keep me informed.
船长 还有些东西
Captain, there's something else.
我重新检查了一下传感器日志 看这个
I was reviewing the sensor logs. Look at this.
当单刃刀号显形时
When the Scimitarde-cloaked,
在第三段电磁波段上出现了瞬时的突起 那儿
there was a momentary spike in the tertiary EM band. There.
你无法想象吧 是瑟拉昂
You're not going to believe this. It's thalaron.
我本以为瑟拉昂射线是理论上存在的
I thought thalaron radiation was theoretical.
这就是为什么我们最初的扫描没有发现它 但是他们找到了 船长
Which is why our initial scans didn't pick it up. But he's got it, Captain.
瑟拉昂研究在联邦是被禁止的
Thalaron research was banned in the Federation
因为它的生物特性
because of its biogenic properties.
它在亚原子水平上有毁灭有机体的能力
It has the ability to consume organic material at the subatomic level.
我不能过高估计瑟拉昂射线的危险 吉恩·卢克.
I can't overestimate the danger of thalaron radiation, Jean-Luc.
极小的数量就能在几秒种内就能杀死
A microscopic amount could kill every living thing
这艘飞船上的所有生命体
on this ship in a matter of seconds.
我明白 继续监视它
I understand. Keep on it.
我想知道他拥有什么以及我们能如何对付他的任何威胁
I want to know what he has and how we can neutralize any threat.
我需要更多的建议
I need options.
这是一个错误 我们正在浪费时间
This was a mistake. We're wasting time.
我的时间
My time.
我会选择怎么花它
And I shall spend it how I choose.
不要忘了我们的任务 辛藏.
Do not forget our mission, Shinzon.
我们必须行动了 立刻!
We must act. Now.
我们回单刃刀号去
We'll return to the Scimitar.
我只是对他很好奇
I was merely curious about him.
请进
Come.
贝弗莉 请进
Beverly, come in.
记得他吗?
Remember him?
- 我记忆里他有点傲慢 - 他是个十足的笨蛋
- He was a bit cocky, as I recall. - He was a damned fool.
自私 野心勃勃 缺乏见识
Selfish. Ambitious. Very much in need of seasoning.
他变好了
He turned out all right.
我真的很想相信辛藏
I really wanted to believe Shinzon.
但是这个瑟拉昂射线很难解释
But this thalaron radiation just can't be explained away.
不论他在追寻什么 但肯定不是和平
Whatever he's after, it isn't peace.
他是不是跟你过去很像?
Is he very much the way you were?
哦 是的
Oh, yes.
- 数据向皮卡特船长报告 - 讲 数据
- Data to Captain Picard. - Go ahead, Data.
船长
Captain,
郭蒂和我已经确定了未授权的电脑访问的来源
Geordi and I have identified the source of the unauthorized computer access.
并且我相信我们已经发现了一种赢得战术优势的方法
And I believe we have found a way to gain a tactical advantage.
我马上就到
On my way.
维尔?
Will?
作为飞船的顾问 我建议你去睡觉
As ship's counselor, I recommend you get some sleep.
度些蜜月
Some honeymoon.
到床上来
Come to bed.
因扎蒂
Imzadi.
他决不会像我这样了解你
He can never know you as I can.
他决不会像我这样触摸你
He can never touch you as I can.
- 这不是真的 - 感觉一下我的嘴唇
- This isn't real! - Then feel my lips.
我和你在一起 因扎蒂
I'm with you, imzadi.
现在我会一直和你在一起
I'll always be with you now.
- 这不是真的! - 蒂安娜...
- This isn't real! - Deanna, what's the matter?
- 不! - 蒂安娜?
- No! - Deanna?
- 蒂安娜! - 不!
- Deanna! - No!
连接中断
The bond has been broken.
再找到她
Find her again.
执政官
Praetor,
我们收到了异频雷达收发机信号
we've received the transponder signal.
它正在恶化 我们没时间玩游戏了
It's accelerating. You have no more time for games.
叫医生准备好
Have the doctors prepare.
传输
Transport.
开始下载
Begin the download.
茶 热的
Tea, hot.
除了轻微的肾上腺素和复合胺过高外
Aside from slightly elevated levels of adrenalin and serotonin,
你相当正常
you're perfectly normal.
蒂安娜 你能描述一下吗?
Deanna, can you describe it?
就像...
It was...
就像一场强奸
It was a violation.
辛藏总督好像有能力进入我的思维
Shinzon's viceroy seems to have the ability to reach into my thoughts.
我已经成为一个负担 我要求解除我的职务
I've become a liability. I request to be relieved of my duties.
拒绝请求
Permission denied.
如果你能忍受更多这样的攻击 我需要你在我身旁
If you can endure more of these assaults, I need you at my side.
现在比以前更需要
Now more than ever.
企业号 远离联邦空间并且...
The Enterprise is far from Federation space...
沃夫! 升起防护罩!
Worf, shields up!
你好 吉恩·卢克.
Hello, Jean-Luc.
我为什么在这里?
Why am I here? Why have you done this?
我很孤独
I was lonely.
- 你想要干什么? - 我需要你血液样品
- What are you going to do? - I need a sample of your blood.
你的博格朋友们说过什么? "一切抵抗都是徒劳"
What is it your Borg friends say? "Resistance is futile."
哦 是的... 机器人
Oh, yes, the android.
- 你不能拒绝的诱饵 - 所有这一切都是为了能抓到我
- The bait you couldn't refuse. - All of this so you could capture me?
不要这么自负了
Don't be so vain.
在我们发现它后 我们做了一些必要的修改
After we found it, we had to make a few modifications.
一个附加的记忆接口 一个隐藏的异频雷达收发机
An extra memory port, a hidden transponder.
现在我们已经得到了访问星际舰队通讯协议
I've now gained access to Starfleet's communications protocol.
我现在知道你们整个舰队的确切位置
I now know the exact location of your entire fleet.
- 你可以走了 - 去那儿?
- You may go. - Where?
滚出我的视线
Out of my sight.
这一切都是为了什么?
What is all this about?
为了命运 皮卡特
It's about destiny, Picard.
- 为了被排斥的瑞曼人 - 你不是瑞曼人
- It's about a Reman outcast. - You're not Reman!
我也不是完全的人类 那么我是什么?
And I'm not quite human. So what am I?
只要你还活着我的生命就毫无意义
My life is meaningless as long as you're still alive.
你存在的时候 我是什么?
What am I while you exist?
一个影子? 一个回声?
A shadow? An echo?
如果你问题是和我有关 那就单独对付我
If your issues are with me, then deal with me.
这和我的飞船没有关系 和联邦没有关系
This has nothing to do with my ship. Nothing to do with the Federation.
哦 但是确实有关系
But it does.
我们将再也不像奴隶一样在任何人面前太不起头了
We will no longer bow before anyone as slaves.
既不在罗穆卢斯人面前 也不在你们强大的联邦面前
Not the Romulans, and not your mighty Federation.
我们是为战争和征服而存在的种族
We are a race bred for war and conquest.
你准备好了为把整个宇宙拖进战争
Are you ready to plunge the entire quadrant into war
来满足你自己个人邪恶的心的准备了吗?
to satisfy your own personal demons?
我对你对自己了解的那么少而感到惊讶
It amazes me how little you know yourself.
- 我绝不会那么做! - 你是我
- I'm incapable of such an act. - You are me.
同样高贵的皮卡特族血液流淌在我们的血管里
The same noble Picard blood runs through our veins.
如果你经历过我的生活 你也会像我这样做的
Had you lived my life, you'd be doing exactly as I am.
所以看看镜子吧 看看你自己
So look in the mirror. See yourself.
考虑一下吧 船长
Consider that, Captain.
我想对你来说已经没有什么更大的痛苦了
I can think of no greater torment for you.
辛藏
Shinzon.
对你来说我也是你的一面镜子
I'm a mirror for you as well.
不会太久了 船长
Not for long, Captain.
恐怕你无法活着目睹
I'm afraid you won't survive to witness
我的胜利了
the victory of the echo over the voice.
他的隐形太完美了
His cloak is perfect.
没有超光速粒子发射 没有剩余的反质子
No tachyon emissions, no residual antiprotons.
好好监视 郭蒂 找到入口
Keep at it, Geordi. Find a way in.
执政官辛藏要见犯人
Praetor Shinzon needs the prisoner.
- 很准时 数据先生 - 我的任务就是成功 长官
- About time, Mr.Data. - My mission was a success, sir.
我找到了射线来源的位置
I've located the source of the radiation.
整个飞船本质上就是一个瑟拉昂射线发动机
This entire ship is essentially a thalaron generator.
它的动力在驾驶台上
Its power relays lead to an activation matrix on the Bridge.
- 那是个武器 - 看起来是这样的
- It's a weapon. - It would appear so.
下载怎么样了?
What about the download?
辛藏相信他已经获得了通讯协议
Shinzon believes he has our communication protocols.
但是他得到的所有星际舰队飞船的位置都是错误的
They will give him inaccurate locations for all Starfleet vessels.
- 干得好 - 长官
- Good work. - Sir.
郭蒂给了我一个原型的紧急传输单元
Geordi supplied me with a prototype for the Emergency Transport Unit.
我建议你使用这个 长官 返回企业号
I recommend you use this, sir, to return to the Enterprise.
- 它只能让我们其中一个使用 - 是的 长官
- It'll only work for one of us. - Yes, sir.
我们会找到一个一起逃脱的办法
We'll find a way off together.
是运行程序的时候了
It is time for the procedure.
快走 渺小的人类动物
Move, puny human animal.
少炫耀 数据
A bit less florid, Data.
杀了他
Kill him!
这边 长官
This way, sir.
距离我们目前位置94米外有一个穿梭机场
There is a shuttlebay 94 meters from our current position.
- 在那里 长官 - 走!
- There it is, sir. - Go!
数据!
Data!
好像有个加了密的安全系统
It appears to have an encrypted security system.
感谢你的敏捷 指挥官!
Alacrity would be appreciated, Commander!
瑞曼语是一种最复杂的语言 使用象形文字
Reman is a most complex language with pictographs
表示某种动词根...
representing certain verb roots...
当我发现那非常迷人的时候 数据 我们真的需要把那门打开!
While I find that fascinating, Data, we really need that door open!
根据飞船载货单 它们是蝎级攻击型飞行物
According to the ship's manifest, they're Scorpion-class attack fliers.
- 数据 你想这是干嘛用的? - 推进器口 长官
- Data, what do you imagine this is? - Port thruster, sir.
你要我来驾驶吗 长官?
Would you like me to drive, sir?
数据 你能打开穿梭机场的门吗?
Data, can you open the shuttlebay doors?
不能 长官 他们在外部入口周围
Negative, sir. They've erected a force field
建立了一个力场
around the external portholes.
那么 看来 只有一个出口了
Well, then, only one way to go.
你认为这是明智之举吗 长官?
Do you think this is a wise course of action, sir?
我们会知道的 数据
We're about to find out, Data.
加强干扰
Power up the disruptors.
- 准备 船长 - 开火
- Ready, Captain. - Fire.
牵引光束 立刻!
Tractor beam, now!
沃夫 用雷达自动跟踪穿梭机
Worf, lock on transporters.
我已经完成了 长官
I have them, sir.
这已经走的太远了
This has gone far enough.
我想我们曾讨论过忍耐 指挥官
I thought we'd discussed patience, Commander.
矿藏正在逐渐消失
Mine is wearing thin.
我们支持你是因为你答应行动
We supported you because you promised action.
但是现在 你耽搁了
And yet, you delay.
企业号非物质的
The Enterprise is immaterial.
在中心区外我们不能做到
It won't even make it out of the Neutral Zone.
在两天之内
And in two days
联邦将会无法逆转的被摧毁
the Federation will be crippled beyond repair.
那能你使满意了吧?
Does that satisfy you?
一会儿
For the moment.
当我回来的时候 你和我
And when I return,
将对关于如何恰当的
you and I shall have a little talk
尊重讨论一下
about showing proper respect.
他的脸怎么了?
What's happening to his face?
指挥官 请稍等
Commander, a moment.
你真的准备让你的双手沾满鲜血吗?
Are you truly prepared to have your hands drenched in blood?
他并不打算打败地球
He's not planning to defeat Earth.
他打算毁灭它
He's planning its annihilation.
他的罪过将给我们以及我们的后代打上烙印时代相传
And his sins will mark us and our children for generations.
我越深入研究他的DNA 我就越迷惑
The more I studied his DNA, the more confusing it got.
最终 我得出一个唯一的结论
Finally, I could come to only one conclusion.
辛藏体内建立了临时的RNA序列
Shinzon was created with temporal RNA sequencing.
他被这样设计以便 在某一点
He was designed so that at a certain point
使他的老化过程加速
his aging process could be accelerated
以更快达到你的年龄
to reach your age more quickly.
他被设计跳过了他30年的生命
He was engineered to skip 30 years of his life.
但是当临时序列没有被激活时
But when the temporal sequencing wasn't activated,
他的细胞结构开始分解
his cellular structure started breaking down.
他正在死亡
He's dying.
死亡?
Dying?
能为他做点什么吗?
Can anything be done for him?
除了从唯一匹配的捐赠者
Nothing, except a complete transfusion
进行完全的换血
from the only donor with compatible DNA.
只有你
You.
- 他还能活多久? - 我不敢确定
- How long does he have? - I can't say for sure.
但是衰退的速度正在加快
But the rate of decay seems to be accelerating.
那么他会来找我的
Then he'll come for me.
兄弟
Brother,
- 我动不了 - 是的
- I cannot move. - No.
我只激活了你的感知和交流子程序
I have only activated your cognitive and communication subroutines.
为什么?
Why?
- 因为你很危险 - 为什么?
- Because you are dangerous. - Why?
你被设计成来收集信息
You have been programmed to gather information
用来对抗这艘飞船
that can be used against this ship.
我不明白
I do not understand.
我明白
I know.
你知道有关辛藏反对联邦的计划吗?
Do you know anything about Shinzon's plans against the Federation?
不知道
No.
你知道有关他飞船的战术能力的资料吗?
Do you have any knowledge of the tactical abilities of his ship?
不知道
No.
现在我能动了吗?
Can I move now?
不行
No.
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
- 我必须停止你的激活状态 - 持续多久?
- I must deactivate you. - For how long?
不确定
Indefinitely.
不确定是多...
How long is...
很久 兄弟
A long time, brother.
它被称作连锁生物脉冲
It's called a cascading biogenic pulse.
瑟拉昂射线的特性是
The unique properties of thalaron radiation
让能量束几乎无限制的膨胀
allow the energy beam to expand almost without limit.
取决于它的射线强度 它能环绕一艘飞船或者一颗行星
Depending on its radiant intensity, it could encompass a ship or a planet.
他建造一种如此大范围的武器
He would only have built a weapon of such scope
只为了一个目的
for one reason.
- 他要毁灭地球 - 你是怎么确定的?
- He's going after Earth. - How can you be certain?
我知道他是怎么想的
I know how he thinks.
毁灭人性 削弱联邦
Destroy humanity, you cripple the Federation.
- 罗穆卢斯星人的侵略 - 无法看穿他的隐形吗?
- The Romulans invade. - No way of penetrating his cloak?
不能
No.
因此他能从任何星际战舰仅10米之外擦身而过
So he could pass within 10 meters of every ship in Starfleet
而不被发现
and they'd never know.
但我们还是有个优势
We do have one advantage, though.
他需要你的血来生存
He needs your blood to live.
- 他可能会先来找你 - 我正指望他来呢
- He might come after you first. - I'm counting on it.
我们已经奉命到1045区
We've been ordered to Sector 10-45.
我们的战舰已经转向到那里和我们会合
Our fleet has been diverted to meet us there.
- 人多力量大 - 是的至少 那是我们所希望的
- Strength in numbers. - Yes, at least that's what we hope.
我们一定要阻止他动用那种武器
He must not be allowed to use that weapon.
其他的事是次要的
All other concerns are secondary.
你们明白吗?
You understand me?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
全体船员 准备战斗
All hands, battle stations.
启动力场
Initiate the force field.
船长个人日志 补充
Captain's Personal Log, supplemental.
我们正全速朝着联邦空间推进
We're heading toward Federation space at maximum warp.
全体船员众志成城
The crew has responded
我对他们充满了期望
with the dedication I've come to expect of them.
就像千万个其他指挥官在千千万个战场上一样
Like a thousand other commanders on a thousand other battlefields,
我期待着黎明的到来
I wait for the dawn.
还有多久?
How long?
只是几个小时的事
A matter of hours.
现在我们必须开始程序了
We must begin the procedure now.
我们到达裂口还有多久?
How long until we reach the Rift?
7分钟
Seven minutes.
数据 我们现在的位置在哪里?
Data, what's our current position?
我们要多久才能和舰队会合?
How soon until we reach the fleet?
以我们当前的速度
At our current velocity,
我们到达1045区大约还要40分钟 长官
we will arrive at Sector 10-45 in approximately 40 minutes, sir.
“眼下我们透过模糊的玻璃看”
"For now we see but through a glass, darkly."
- 长官? - 他说他是一面镜子
- Sir? - He said he is a mirror.
- 是你的吗 长官? - 是的
- Of you, sir? - Yes.
我不同意
I do not agree.
虽然你们有相同的遗传结构
Although you share the same genetic structure,
你们生活中的事件造就了一个独特的个体
the events of your life have created a unique individual.
如果我经历了他的生活
If I had lived his life,
我也有可能会泯灭人性吗?
is it possible that I would have rejected my humanity?
B-4在身体上和我是一模一样的
The B-4 is physically identical to me
并且虽然他的神经线路不够发达
although his neural pathways are not as advanced.
但是即使他们先进的 他也不是我
But even if they were, he would not be me.
- 你怎么能这么确定? - 我立志 长官 要不断超越自我
- How can you be sure? - I aspire, sir, to be better than I am.
B-4不会 辛藏也不会
B-4 does not. Nor does Shinzon.
我们正在通过贝森裂口 长官
We are passing through the Bassen Rift, sir.
当我们清除它时 投射会返回
The projection will return when we have cleared it.
它会妨碍我们从星际舰队绘制法传出的上行线吗?
It's interfering with our uplink from Starfleet cartography?
裂口影响所有的长途通讯...
The Rift affects all long-range...
瑞克指挥官 进行逃逸操作
Commander Riker, evasive maneuvers.
瞄准目标的武器系统和防护罩
Target weapons systems and shields.
我不想企业号 被摧毁
I don't want the Enterprise destroyed.
你能学会在黑暗下看见东西吗 船长?
Can you learn to see in the dark, Captain?
报告
Report.
他通过隐形状态开火 我们不能锁定他
He's firing from the cloak. We can't get a lock.
他用他第一次射击瘫痪了我们的航线
He disabled our warp drive with his first shot.
我们只能推进了 船长
We only have impulse, Captain.
沃夫先生 准备展开所有移相器 零提升
Mr.Worf, prepare a full phaser spread, zero elevation.
标记我们所有储备
All banks on my mark.
扫描防护效果 准备 光子鱼雷
Scan for shield impacts. Stand by photon torpedoes.
是 长官
Aye, sir.
开火
Fire!
你太慢了 老头子
You're too slow, old man.
攻击模式 辛藏第八号
Attack pattern Shinzon Theta.
我们正在失去背部防护!
We are losing dorsal shields.
全轴旋转到左舷
Full axis rotation to port!
发射所有腹部移相器
Fire all ventral phasers.
对单刃刀号 损伤太小
Minimal damage to the Scimitar.
防守模式 科尔克第五级 让所有防护网联网 郭蒂
Defensive pattern Kirk Epsilon. Get the shields online, Geordi.
我已经准备了
Already on it.
婥维顾问 报告驾驶舱的情况
Counselor Troi, report to the Bridge.
船长 我们有通讯联系
Captain, we are being hailed.
接到屏幕上
On screen.
皮卡特船长...
Captain Picard,
你欢迎我到你的准备室吗?
will you join me in your Ready Room?
你不能跟踪我的全息发射器 船长
You can't trace my holographic emitters, Captain,
因此不要在麻烦了 并且你也不能和舰队联系
so don't bother. And you can't contact Starfleet.
现在只有我们俩了 吉恩·卢克
It's just the two of us now, Jean-Luc.
就应该这样
As it should be.
- 你为什么在这里? - 来接受你的投降
- Why are you here? - To accept your surrender.
我随时都可以轻而易举的把你摧毁
I can clearly destroy you at any time.
减弱你的防护罩 让我把你传输到我的飞船上
Lower your shields and allow me to transport you to my ship.
那企业号呢?
And the Enterprise?
我对你的稀奇古怪的船没有兴趣 船长
I have little interest in your quaint vessel, Captain.
看着我 辛藏
Look at me, Shinzon.
你的心 你的双手
Your heart, your hands,
你的眼睛和我是一样的
your eyes are the same as mine.
在你体内流动的血液 原料物质都是一样的
The blood pumping within you, the raw material is the same.
我们有同样的潜力
We have the same potential.
- 那是过去了 船长 - 那也能是未来
- That's the past, Captain. - It can be the future.
埋藏在你内心深处
Buried deep within you,
在多年的痛苦和愤怒之下
beneath all the years of pain and anger,
还有一些东西从来都没有被滋养过
there is something that has never been nurtured,
潜力能使你成为一个更好的人
the potential to make yourself a better man
那才是做人的根本
and that is what it is to be human.
努力超于自我
To make yourself more than you are.
哦 是的
Oh, yes.
我了解你
I know you.
曾几何时你仰望群星
There was a time you looked at the stars
梦想那可能是什么
and dreamed of what might be.
幼稚的梦想 船长
Childish dreams, Captain.
已经迷失在瑞摩斯星蒂里塞矿藏里了
Lost in the dilithium mines of Remus.
我是现在所见的样子
I am what you see now.
我看到了比那更多的东西 我看到你会是什么样子
I see more than that. I see what you could be.
瑞摩斯星的辛藏和吉恩·卢克·皮卡特
The man who is Shinzon of Remus and Jean-Luc Picard
决不会消灭整个行星上的人口
could never exterminate the population of an entire planet.
他应该比那更好
He's better than that.
他是由他的生活决定的
He is what his life has made him.
那么 你会怎样处理那样的生活呢? 浪费在一片仇恨之中吗?
And what will you do with that life? Waste it in a blaze of hatred?
还有更好的办法
There is a better way.
太迟了
It's too late.
不 不迟 你仍然还有机会 现在做一个正确的决定吧
Never. You still have a choice. Make the right one now.
- 我不能违背我的本性 - 不 你可以
- I can't fight what I am. - Yes, you can.
我会给你展示我真正的本性
I'll show you my true nature.
我们的本性
Our nature.
当地球毁灭的时候
And as Earth dies, remember:
记住 我将永远是永恒的瑞摩斯星的辛藏
I will always, forever be Shinzon of Remus.
我的声音将在你的声音逐渐
And my voice shall echo through time long after
在记忆中消退之后在时空中长久的回响
yours has faded to a dim memory.
两艘飞船显形 长官 若米兰人
Two ships de-cloaking, sir. Romulan.
船长
Captain.
我想不会再糟了
Just when I thought this couldn't get any worse.
我们收到通讯联系
We are being hailed.
接到屏幕上
On screen.
皮卡特船长 维多号 战舰指挥官德纳储
Captain Picard, Commander Donatra of the warbird Valdore.
我们能提供援助吗?
Might we be of assistance?
援助?
Assistance?
帝国考虑到事关国内安全
The Empire considers this a matter of internal security.
我们很遗憾你们被卷了进来
We regret you've become involved.
指挥官 这场战斗结束后 我请你喝一杯
Commander, when this is over, I owe you a drink.
若米兰啤酒 船长 让我们开始工作吧
Romulan ale, Captain. Let's get to work.
你们都听见女士说的了
You heard the lady.
让我们开始工作吧
Let's go to work.
沃夫先生 调整我们的攻击和维多号 战术指挥官一起
Mr.Worf, coordinate our attack with the Valdore Tactical Officer.
形成在防护罩效果下三角攻击
Triangulate all fire on any shield impacts.
是 长官
Aye, sir.
后防护罩降低到40％
Aft shields down to 40%.
保持我们的船首正对单刃刀号 向前防护罩补充能量
Keep our bow on the Scimitar. Auxiliary power to forward shields.
是 长官
Aye, sir.
瞄准侧翼战舰 运送我标记的所有干扰储备
Target the flanking warbird. All forward disruptor banks on my mark.
- 前防护罩降低到10％ - 把我们的头掉过来
- Forward shields down to 10%. - Bring us about.
放下后舱门部分隐形 准备紧急停止
Drop cloak on the aft port quadrant. Prepare for full emergency stop.
- 什么? - 你听见我说的了吗!
- What? - You heard me!
他正在失去他的隐形 准备运送所有干扰储备
He's losing his cloak. Stand by all forward disruptor banks.
她就在我们上面
She's almost on us.
还没有
Not yet.
- 还没有 - 全停 开火!
- Praetor. - Full stop. Fire!
恢复后部隐形并把头掉转过来
Restore the aft cloak and bring us about.
恐怕那杯酒不得不等等了 船长
I'm afraid that drink will have to wait, Captain.
- 你有生命支持吗? - 目前还有
- You have life support? - For the moment.
- 但是我们会死在水里的 - 明白
- But we're dead in the water. - Understood.
我们正在失去
We're losing structural integrity
从12到17号甲板 4到10区的结构整体性
on Decks 12 through 17, sections 4 through 10.
开启紧急力场
Emergency Force fields are holding.
撤掉那些甲板 并把场能转送到前防护罩
Evacuate those decks. Re-route field power to forward shields.
船长
Captain,
我想我有办法找到他们
I think I may have a way to find them.
准备侧向运转 启动所有右舷干扰
Prepare for a lateral run, all starboard disruptors.
怎么了?
What is it?
她在这里
She's here.
他在抵抗我
He's resisting me.
不!
No!
记住我
Remember me.
立即!
Now.
任意开火
Fire at will.
准备登船把皮卡特给我带来
Prepare a boarding party. Bring me Picard.
你
You.
恢复隐形!
Get the cloak back!
瞄准所有防护罩坐标 β3 所有干扰 开火
Target all shield coordinates, Beta-3. All disruptors fire!
船长 我们失去了在29号甲板的中部防护罩
Captain, we've lost ventral shielding on Deck 29!
转移所有动力和补给
Divert all power and compensate.
- 入侵警报 - 大副
- Intruder alert. - Number One.
- 我们走 - 详细报告29号甲板安全情况
- Let's go. - Security detail to Deck 29.
罗穆卢斯人为荣誉而战
The Romulans fought with honor.
是的 沃夫先生
Yes, they did, Mr.Worf.
沃夫 掩护我
Worf, cover me.
医疗队请到驾驶室
Medical teams to the Bridge.
报告
Report.
我们耗尽了我们所有补充的光子鱼雷弹
We have exhausted our complement of photon torpedoes.
移相器储备减少到4% 长官
Phaser banks are down to 4%, sir.
如果我们用集中模式把我们所有移相器瞄准会怎么样?
What if we targeted all our phasers in a concentrated pattern?
单刃刀号的防护罩依然在70% 那没有什么差别 船长
The Scimitar shields are still at 70%. It would make no difference, Captain.
他正在做什么?
What's he doing?
他想看看我
He wants to look me in the eye.
我们逮住他了
We've got him.
他认为他确切的知道我将做什么
He thinks he knows exactly what I'm going to do.
郭蒂 把所有动力转移到引擎上 把生命支持拿走 如果必要的话
Geordi, divert all power to the engines. Take it from life support, if you have to.
把你得到所有都给我
Give me everything you've got.
准备好了 船长
Ready, Captain.
我们接到通讯联络 长官
We are being hailed, sir.
蒂安娜 准备 打开一个通道
Deanna, stand by. Open a channel.
- 我希望你依然活着 吉恩·卢克 - 哦 是的 我还活着
- I hope you're still alive, Jean-Luc. - Oh. Yes, I am.
你不认为是投降的时候了吗?
Don't you think it's time to surrender?
为什么你的船员必须死?
Why should the rest of your crew have to die?
辛藏 我想我没有告诉过你
Shinzon, I don't think I ever told you
关于我的第一个学院评估
about my first Academy evaluation.
特别是 我被认为是极端的
In particular, I was thought to be extremely
自负
overconfident.
船长 我很乐意听你高谈阔论 我真的以为...
Captain, as much as I enjoy listening to you talk, I really think...
标记我的记录 蒂安娜 全体船员 准备撞击
On my mark, Deanna. All hands, brace for impact.
前进
Engage.
左满舵!
Hard to port!
把所有动力转换到引擎
Divert all power to the engines.
全速后退
Full reverse.
现在重新装备
Reconfiguring now.
电脑 准备自毁程序Ω
Computer, stand by auto-destruct sequence Omega.
确认吉恩·卢克·皮卡特的声音模式
Recognize voice pattern Jean-Luc Picard.
授权: α－α－3－0－5
Authorization: Alpha-Alpha-3-0-5.
自毁程序中断
Auto-destruct is offline.
干扰没有起作用 长官
Disruptors are not functional, sir.
配置武器
Deploy the weapon.
毁了那艘船上的所有东西
Kill everything on that ship,
然后确定一个到地球路线
then set a course for Earth.
我们必须完成我们的任务
We must complete our mission.
矩阵启动
Matrix initiated.
激活瑟拉昂射线传送的排列程序
Sequencing procedure for thalaron radiation transfer activated.
有些理想是值得我们献出生命 不是吗 吉恩·卢克?
Some ideals are worth dying for, aren't they, Jean-Luc?
瑟拉昂混合程序启动
Thalaron intermix procedure initiated.
开始配置目标武器
Deployment of targeting arms commencing.
离开火还有多久?
How long until he can fire?
目标序列应该在大约7分钟后启动 船长
The targeting sequence should take about seven minutes, Captain.
当目标武器全部配置好后 在驾驶室的矩阵
When the targeting arms are fully deployed,
将传递瑟拉昂射线
the matrix on the Bridge will relay the thalaron radiation
集中到他们顶端的射击点
to the firing points at their tips.
企业号 上没有人能幸存
No one on the Enterprise will survive.
- 他能怎么样? 他会杀了你的 - 再也不和我相关了
- How can he? He'll kill you. - It's not about me anymore.
准备点对点传送
Prepare for a site-to-site transport.
船长 我认为不要进行传送...
I don't think that the transport...
- 这是命令 指挥官 - 长官 让我去吧
- That's an order, Commander. - Sir, allow me to go.
- 数据 这是我必须做的 - 长官
- Data, this is something I have to do. - Sir.
- 数据 - 你来驾驶 指挥官
- Data. - You have the Bridge, Commander.
在你和单刃刀号之间尝试保持距离
Try and put some distance between you and the Scimitar.
- 赶快 拉佛吉先生 - 是 长官
- Now, Mr.La Forge. - Aye, sir.
完了 传送器坏了
That's it. Transporters are down.
系统有保险丝装置
System is fused.
婥维顾问 请下达指令 郭蒂 跟我来
Counselor Troi, please assume command. Geordi, come with me.
瑟拉昂混合等级: 30%
Thalaron intermix level: 30%.
4分钟后达到发射序列
Four minutes to firing sequence.
瑟拉昂混合等级: 50%
Thalaron intermix level: 50%.
3分钟后达到发射序列
Three minutes to firing sequence.
瑟拉昂混合等级: 60%
Thalaron intermix level: 60%.
2分钟后达到发射序列
Two minutes to firing sequence.
瑟拉昂混合等级: 80%
Thalaron intermix level: 80%.
我很高兴我们现在在一起了
I'm glad we're together now.
我们的命运完整了
Our destiny is complete.
1分钟后达到发射序列
One minute to firing sequence.
瑟拉昂混合等级 完成
Thalaron intermix level completed.
30秒后达到发射序列
30 seconds to firing sequence.
再见
Goodbye.
十 九 八
Ten, nine, eight,
七 六 五
seven, six, five,
四 三 二
four, three, two...
数据?
Data?
船长
Captain.
是数据
It's Data.
船长 我们收到通讯联系
Captain, we're being hailed.
接到屏幕上
On-screen.
打开一个频道
Open a channel.
这是维多号 指挥官德纳储
This is Commander Donatra of the Valdore.
我们正在派遣携带医疗人员和供给的穿梭机
We're dispatching shuttles with medical personnel and supplies.
谢谢 指挥官
Thank you, Commander.
今天你在若米兰帝国你赢得个朋友 船长
You've earned a friend in the Romulan Empire today, Captain.
我希望这是许多中的第一个
I hope, the first of many.
维多号 中断通讯
Valdore out.
郭蒂 准备穿梭机到达的机场
Geordi, prepare the shuttlebay for arrivals.
他们 呃 他们不知道我们的程序
They don't know our procedures.
- 把门打开就行了 - 我会处理的 船长
- Just open the doors. - I'll take care of it, Captain.
你来控制驾驶 大副
You have the Bridge, Number One.
谢谢
Thank you.
为缺席的朋友
To absent friends.
为家庭
To family.
我第一次见到数据的时候
First time I saw Data,
他正在靠在全息舱的一棵树上学吹口哨
he was leaning against a tree in the holodeck, trying to whistle.
那是我见过最搞笑的事了
Funniest thing I ever saw.
无论他怎么做 他都不能吹出正确的调子
No matter what he did, he couldn't get the tune right.
那是什么歌?
What was that song?
不记得那歌了
Can't remember the song.
来
Come.
- 维尔 - 请求登陆 长官
- Will. - Permission to disembark, sir.
批准
Granted.
那么 泰坦号 离开去哪里?
So, where's the Titan off to?
中心区
The Neutral Zone.
我们将领导新的特遣部队
We're heading up the new task force.
显然 若米兰人对谈话很感兴趣
Apparently, the Romulans are interested in talking.
呃 对这工作我想不起更合适的人选了
I can't think of a better man for the job.
我可以问一下 你的第一个命令只是个建议吗?
If I may, just a word of advice about your first command?
一切
Anything.
当你的大副坚持你不能离开使命...
When your First Officer insists that you can't go on away missions...
别理他 我正打算这样
Ignore him. I intend to.
和你一起工作是种荣誉
Serving with you has been an honor.
是我的荣誉 船长
The honor was mine, Captain.
我不知道是否所有这些造成这些感觉
I don't know if all this has made any sense.
但是我想你知道他应该是什么样的人
But I wanted you to know what kind of man he was.
在他寻求和我们更像的过程中
In his quest to be more like us,
他帮助我们看清了做为人类的真正意义
he helped us to see what it means to be human.
我的...
My...
我的兄弟不是一个人类
My brother was not human.
不 他不是
No, he wasn't.
但是他创造的奇迹
But his wonder,
他对人类本性各方面的好奇
his curiosity about every facet of human nature
让我们看清了我们自己本身最好的方面
allowed all of us to see the best parts of ourselves.
他发展了自我
He evolved.
他接受改变
He embraced change
因为他总想超越自我
because he always wanted to be better than he was.
我...
I...
我不明白
I do not understand.
那么 我希望有一天你能明白
Well, I hope someday you will.
船长 航线引擎准备待命
Captain, the warp engines are ready to go online.
我马上就来 请通知拉佛吉指挥官
I'm on my way. Please inform Commander La Forge.
我们以后再聊
We'll talk later.
∮ 从来没见过太阳 ∮
∮ Never saw the sun ∮
∮ 照耀出如此光亮 ∮
∮ Shining so bright ∮
∮ 从来没见过事情 ∮
∮ Never saw things ∮
∮ 发展如此顺利 ∮
∮ Going so right ∮